https://pridewinnipeg.com/privacy-policy/

Skip to content
Menu
Close
PRIVACY POLICY
Pride Winnipeg Festival is committed to safeguarding the personal information entrusted to us by our stakeholders. We manage personal information in accordance with Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA) and other applicable laws. This statement outlines the principles and practices we follow in protecting personal information.The Pride Winnipeg Stakeholder Privacy Policy applies to any person providing services on our behalf. A copy of this policy is provided to any stakeholder on request.WHAT IS PERSONAL INFORMATION?Personal information means information about an identifiable individual. This includes an individual’s name, home address and phone number, age, gender, marital or family status, an identifying number, financial information, educational history, etc.WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?We collect only the personal information that we need for the purposes of providing services to our stakeholders, including personal information needed to:Deliver requested products and services.Sign up an individual as a member.Send out organization membership information.We normally collect stakeholder personal information directly from our stakeholders. We may collect information from other persons with the consent of the individual or as authorized by law.We shall inform our stakeholders, before or at the time of collecting personal information, of the purposes for which we are collecting the information. The only time we do not have to provide this notification is when a stakeholder volunteers information for an obvious purpose (for example, producing a credit card to pay a membership fee when the information will be used only to process the payment).CONSENT.We ask for consent to collect, use or disclose stakeholder personal information, except in specific circumstances where collection, use or disclosure without consent is authorized or required by law. We may assume consent in cases where the individual volunteers information for an obvious purpose.We assume consent to continue to use and, where applicable, disclose personal information that we have already collected, for the purpose for which the information was collected.We ask for express consent for some purposes and may not be able to provide certain services if an individual is unwilling to provide consent to the collection, use or disclosure of certain personal information. Where express consent is needed, we will normally ask stakeholders to provide their consent orally (in person, by telephone), or in writing (by signing a consent form).A stakeholder may withdraw consent to the use and disclosure of personal information at any time, unless the personal information is necessary for us to fulfill our legal obligations. We will respect their decision, but we may not be able to provide them with certain products and services if we do not have the necessary personal information.We may collect, use or disclose stakeholder personal information without consent only as authorized by law. For example, we may not request consent when the collection, use or disclosure is to determine suitability for an honor or award, or in an emergency that threatens life, health or safety.HOW DO WE USE AND DISCLOSE PERSONAL INFORMATION?We use and disclose stakeholder personal information only for the purpose, for which the information was collected, except as authorized by law. For example, we may use stakeholder contact information to deliver goods.If we are to use or disclose an individual’s personal information for any new business purpose, we will ask them for consent. We will not seek consent if the law allows this (e.g. the law allows organizations to use personal information without consent for the purpose of collecting a debt).WHAT IS PERSONAL STAFF INFORMATION?Personal staff information is personal information about an employee or volunteer which is collected, used or disclosed solely for the purposes of establishing, managing or terminating an employment relationship or a volunteer work relationship. Personal staff information may, in some circumstances, include a Social Insurance Number, a performance review, etc.We will collect, use and disclose your personal employee information without consent only for the purposes of establishing, managing or ending the employment or volunteer relationship. We will provide current employees and volunteers with prior notice about what information we collect, use or disclose and our purpose for doing so.WHAT PERSONAL STAFF INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT, USE AND DISCLOSE?We collect, use and disclose personal staff information to meet the following purposes:Determining eligibility for employment or volunteer work, including verifying qualifications and references.Establishing training and development requirements.Assessing performance and managing performance issues if they arise.Administering pay and benefits (paid employees only).Processing employee work-related claims (e.g. benefits, workers’ compensation, insurance claims) (paid employees only).Complying with requirements of funding bodies (e.g. lottery grants).Complying with applicable laws (e.g. Canada Income Tax Act, Manitoba Employment Standards Code)We only collect, use and disclose the amount and type of personal employee information that is reasonable to meet the above purposes. The following is a list of personal employee information that we may collect, use and disclose to meet those purposes:Contact information such as name, home address, telephone number.Criminal background checksEmployment or volunteer information such as a resume (including educational background, work history and references), reference information and interview notes, letters of offer and acceptance of employment, policy acknowledgement forms, background verification information, workplace performance evaluations, emergency contacts, etc.Benefit information such as forms relating to applications or changes to health and insurance benefits including medical and dental care, life insurance, short and long term disability, etc. (paid employees only)Financial information, such as pay cheque deposit information and tax-related information, including Social Insurance Numbers (paid employees only)Other personal information required for the purposes of our employment or volunteer relationshipWe will inform our employees and volunteers of any new purpose for which we will collect, use, or disclose personal employee information, or we will obtain their consent, before or at the time the information is collected.WHAT INFORMATION DO WE PROVIDE FOR EMPLOYMENT/VOLUNTEER REFERENCE?In some cases, after employment or volunteer relationship with us ends, we will be contacted by other organizations and asked to provide a reference. It is our policy not to disclose personal information about our employees and volunteers to other organizations who request references without consent. The personal information we normally provide in a reference includes:Confirmation that an individual was an employee or volunteer, including the position, and date range of the employment or volunteeringGeneral information about an individual’s job duties and information about the employee or volunteer’s ability to perform job duties and success in the employment or volunteer relationshipHOW DO WE SAFEGUARD PERSONAL INFORMATION?We will make every reasonable effort to ensure that personal information is accurate and complete. We will rely on individuals to notify us if there is a change to their personal information that may affect their relationship with the organization. If an individual is aware of an error in our information about them, they must let us know and we will correct it on request wherever possible. In some cases we may request for a written request for correction.We will protect personal information in a manner appropriate for the sensitivity of the information. We will make every reasonable effort to prevent any loss, misuse, disclosure or modification of personal information, as well as any unauthorized access to personal information.We will use appropriate security measures when destroying personal information, including shredding paper records and permanently deleting electronic records.We will retain personal information only as long as is reasonable to fulfill the purposes for which the information was collected or for legal or business purposes.ACCESS TO RECORDS CONTAINING PERSONAL INFORMATION.Individuals have a right to access their own personal information in a record that is in the custody or under the control of Pride Winnipeg Festival, subject to some exceptions. For example, organizations are required under the Personal Information Protection Act to refuse to provide access to information that would reveal personal information about another individual.If we refuse a request in whole or in part, we will provide the reasons for the refusal. In some cases where exceptions to access apply, we may withhold that information and provide an individual with the remainder of the record.Individuals may make a request for access to their personal information by writing to the Vice-President, Corporate Affairs. They must provide sufficient information in their request to allow us to identify the information they are seeking.An individual may also request information about our use of their personal information and any disclosure of that information to persons outside our organization. In addition, they may request a correction of an error or omission in their personal information.We will respond to their request within 7 calendar days, unless an extension is granted. We may charge a reasonable fee to provide information, but not to make a correction. We do not charge fees when the request is for personal staff information. We will advise the individual of any fees that may apply before beginning to process their request.
Search for:
English (Canada)
English (Canada)
Français du Canada
RECENT NEWS
Pride Winnipeg Statement of Support for Black Lives Matter
Pride Winnipeg announces postponement of Fierté Canada Pride festival to 2022
